A Guide to the Record Group Vertical Files, 1960s-present
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
- Record Group 6 - Division of Operations
  - RG 6/1 - Vice President for Operations
    The position of Vice-President for Administration was established in 1966 in a reorganization. In 2017, the position became the Vice President for Operations and began reporting to the newly created Senior Vice President for Operations and Administration.
  - RG 6/2 - Capital Construction and Renovations
    In 1967, the Office of the Planning Engineer became Physical Plant Planning. It was later known as Physical Plant Planning and Construction and as the Office of University Design and Construction. The department eventually moved to the Facilties Department [RG 6/3]. Around 2016, the department was renamed Facilities Operations and Construction, and around 2017, the department was renamed Capital Construction and Renovations.
    May include Physical concerns of space
    See also RG 6/3.
    - RG 6/2 - Capital Construction and Renovations (Information)
    - RG 6/2 - Capital Construction and Renovations (Publications)
  - RG 6/3 - Facilities Department [items also in Oversize Box 1]
    Facilities Services was formerly the Physical Plant Department and prior to that Buildings and Grounds through 1977. It was renamed the Facilties Department in 2016. This department also oversees Capital Construction and Renovations [RG 6/2].
    May include University Planning and Architecture [see also RG 6/3/13]; Campus Master Plan; VT Electric Service; Renovation Design section; Public auction; Telecommunications master plan; Wells on campus; Planning and Engineering Department; Dining Hall Operations; Space management program; Girls Day; University Building Official; Construction Management Program; Women in Construction Week
    See also RG 6/2; RG 6/3/13.
    - RG 6/3 - Facilities Department (Information)
    - RG 6/3 - Facilities Department (Publications and Maps)
    - RG 6/3a - Associate Vice President and Chief Facilities Officer
      The Vice President for Facilities became the Associate Vice President and Chief Facilities Officer.
    - RG 6/3b - University Campus Master Plan
    - RG 6/3/1 - Police and Security [items also in Oversize Box 1]
      May include Safe Ride Program; Bomb hoax; Faculty-Staff Police Academy; Threat Assessment Team
      See also RG 8/2/8a for Crimes and Misdemeanors.
      - RG 6/3/1a - Environmental Health and Safety Services
        The Office of Safety and Health was renamed Environmental Health and Safety Services in January 1993.
        May include Blizzard of 1993; University health and safety policies; Flood of 1992; Virginia Tech Award for Safety Excellence
        - RG 6/3/1a - Environmental Health and Safety Services, through 1991 (Information)
        - RG 6/3/1a - Environmental Health and Safety Services, 1992-present (Information)
        - RG 6/3/1a - Environmental Health and Safety Services (Publications)
    - RG 6/3/2 - Buildings and Grounds
      See also RG 6/2 for University Design and Construction.
      - RG 6/3/2a - General buildings
        May include Articles on multiple buildings and contruction projects; Bricks for buildings; Dedications of buildings [see also specific buildings]; Faculty apartments; Virginia Tech trails; Alumni Mall; Campus overview
      - RG 6/3/2b - Specific buildings
        - RG 6/3/2b - Specific buildings, A-D
          May include Amphitheatre (Garden Theatre) [see also RG 8/8/1b]; Creativity and Innovation District; Anaerobic Bacteria Laboratory
          See RG 6/3/3 for Airport; RG 8/8/1b for Amphitheatre (Garden Theatre).
        - RG 6/3/2b - Ambler Johnson Hall (East AJ and West AJ; dorm)
        - RG 6/3/2b - Athletic facilties
          May include Articles on multiple athletic facilities; the Field House (1914-1923); Merryman Center; Jamerson Athletic Center; Beamer-Lawson Indoor Practice Facility; Hahn Hurst Basketball Practice Center; South Recreation Field; Williams Clubhouse; Johnson-Miller Outdoor Track Complex
          See also individual buildings.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Burchard Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Burruss Hall
          May include Carillon [see also RG 6/3/9]
        - RG 6/3/2b - Cassell Coliseum
          The Student Activities and Physical Education Building was completed in 1964. During initial phases, the building was called the Fieldhouse. It was renamed Cassell Coliseum in 1976.
          May include basketball stadium
          See RG 6/3/2b for the Field House (1914-1923).
        - RG 6/3/2b - Cheatham Hall
          May include Kopjafa (April 16, 2007, memorial column)
        - RG 6/3/2b - Classroom Building
        - RG 6/3/2b - Cowgill Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Davidson Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Derring Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Dietrick Dining Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Dining Halls
          May include Mess Hall
          See also individual building names; RG 8/2/1j.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Dorms, General
          May include Articles on multiple dorms; Dormitories; Residence Halls; Praire Quad Residence Hall; Upper quadrangle (eight brick dorms); Lower quadrangle (nine dorms on south side of Drillfield); Building 253 (Extension apartment house, women's auxiliary dorm)
          See also individual building names; RG 8/2/1.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Dorms, A-J
          May include Barringer Hall; Brodie Hall; Campbell Hall (west stone dorm); Cochrane Hall; Eggleston Hall (east stone dorm); Johnson Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Dorms, K-Q
          May include Lee Hall; Major Williams Hall; Miles Hall; Monteith Hall; Newman Hall; O'Shaugnessey Hall; Pritchard Hall; Payne Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Dorms, R-Z
          May include New Cadet Hall; Shanks Hall (Barracks No. 4 and No. 7 united); Thomas Hall; University Club Building; Vawter Hall; Woolwine House; former Sigma Phi Epsilon house [Sig Ep House] / Innovate
        - RG 6/3/2b - Durham Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Specific buildings, E-G
          May include Fralin Biotechnology Center / Fralin Life Sciences Institute; Food Science and Technology building; Gazebo; Global Business and Analytics Complex
        - RG 6/3/2b - Engel Hall
          Completed in 1961, the Biochemistry and Nutrition Building was renamed Engel Hall in 1988.
        - RG 6/3/2b - English Field at Atlantic Union Park
          English Field was completed in 1989, and it was renamed English Field at Union Park on March 21, 2016, named after donor Union Bank & Trust. On May 20, 2019, it was renamed English Field at Atlantic Union Bank Park when the bank changed names.
          May include Baseball stadium; Tech Park
        - RG 6/3/2b - Goodwin Hall
          Initially called the Signature Building, Goodwin Hall was completed in 2014.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Graduate Life Center at Donaldson Brown (GLC; dorm)
          The Faculty Center was built in 1935 for faculty housing until 1965. The building was expanded in 1968, when it became the Continuing Education Center. The center was also known as Alumni Hall, the Donaldson Brown Center for Continuing Education, and the Donaldson Brown Hotel and Conference Center. In 2006, it was renamed the Graduate Life Center at Donaldson Brown (GLC) and serves as graduate housing and graduate education center.
          This is for the physical building, not administration or events. May include Donaldson Brown Hotel and Conference Center; Continuing Education Center
          See also RG 26/3; RG 22; RG 8/2/1; RG 35/4.
        - RG 6/3/2b - The Grove (The President's Home)
          Built in 1902, the President's House was renamed The Grove in 1988. From 1970 to 1989, the president lived in a home on Rainbow Ridge, which was donated to the university in 1974 then sold in 1991.
          May include Building 274
          See also Rainbow Ridge, RG 6/3/2b.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Specific buildings, H-K [items also in Oversize Box 1]
          May include Fout Barn; Hutcheson Hall; Holden Hall; Hyperloop test track
        - RG 6/3/2b - Hancock Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Hahn Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Henderson Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Human and Agricultural Biosciences Building
        - RG 6/3/2b - Inn at Virginia Tech and Skelton Conference Center and the Holtzman Alumni Center
          See also RG 35/3 for administration and programming.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Johnston Student Center
          The G. Burke Johnston Student Center was built in 1990. It is known as the Johnston Student Center or the GBJ.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Kelly Hall
          The Institutte for Critical Technology and Applied Science (ICTAS) built the ICTAS Building in 2009. It was renamed Kelly Hall in 2013.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Specific buildings, L-O
          May include Martin Observatory; Anderson Observatory; Log cabin and smokehouse; William E. Avery Animal Health and Reserch Center; National Surface Transportation Safety Center for Excellence
        - RG 6/3/2b - Lane Hall
          Barracks No. 1, a dormitory, opened in 1888. In 1952, it was renamed Lane Hall. In 1967, the dormitory was turned into an academic building, and in 2015, it was added to the National Register of Historic Places.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Lane Stadium
        - RG 6/3/2b - Litton-Reeves Hall
          The Animal Sciences Building was dedicated in 1981 and rededicated as Litton-Reaves Hall in 1989.
        - RG 6/3/2b - McBryde Hall
          The original McBryde Hall was completed in 1917 and razed in 1966. It was replaced with the new McBryde Hall in 1971.
        - RG 6/3/2b - McComas Hall
          A recreation and wellness center was first proposed in 1989. After delays, the Student Health and Fitness Center was completed in 1998. It was renamed McComas Hall.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Moss Center for the Arts
        - RG 6/3/2b - Newman Library
          The Carol M. Newman Library opened in 1955, on the same location of the previous library, which burned down in 1953.
          See also RG 23.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Norris Hall
          The New Engineering Building was completed in 1962. It was renamed Norris Hall in 1967. The hall was one of the sites of the April 16, 2007, tragedy, where 30 of 32 faculty and students were killed.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Owens Dining Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Specific buildings, P-R
          May include Rainbow Ridge (president's home, 1970-1989); Plantation Road Research Park Facility; Research and Demonstration Facility
          See RG 6/3/7 for Pete Dye River Course.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Pamplin Hall
          The new Commerce Hall was opened in 1957, and it was renamed Pamplin Hall in 1969. (The original Commerce Hall was demolished in 1957.)
        - RG 6/3/2b - Prices Fork Research Station
          Prices Fork Research Station is also called Prices Fork Research Facility.
          May include Environmental Systems Laboratory and FutureHAUS fire in 2017
          See also RG 14/8 for FutureHAUS.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Randolph Hall
          Completed in the summer of 1952, the Mechanical Engineering Laboratory was renamed Randolph Hall in December.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Rector Field House
          The Charles W. Rector Field House was completed in 1971.
          May include Madison Square Garden track
        - RG 6/3/2b - Rector Tennis Pavilion
        - RG 6/3/2b - Robeson Hall
          The Physics Building opened in 1960, renamed Robeson Hall in 1969.
          May include Nuclear reactor [see also RG 15/9; RG 18/9]
        - RG 6/3/2b - Specific buildings, S-T
          May include Student Services Building; Sterrett Facilities Complex; Smyth Hall; Seitz Hall; Theatre 101; Schiffert Health Center building; Shanks Hall; Smith Career Center; Sardo Pallet and Container Research Laboratory; Snyder Flagpole Plaza (Upper Quad)
        - RG 6/3/2b - Shultz Dining Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Slusher Hall (dorm)
        - RG 6/3/2b - Squires Student Center
          May include Squires Student Center's 75th Anniversary; Perspective Gallery; Student Activities Building
          See also RG 31/19.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Steger Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - Torgersen Hall
          Torgersen Hall was completed in 2000. Prior to completion, the building was called Advanced Communications and Information Technology Center. The Torg Bridge extends over the Alumni Mall and connects the Hall to Newman Library.
        - RG 6/3/2b - Turner Place (dining hall)
        - RG 6/3/2b - Specific buildings, U-Z
          May include University City Office Building; Visitor's Center; Visitor and Undergraduate Admissions Center; Virginia-Maryland Regional College of Veterinary Medicine building; VPI-Blacksburg Sewage Plant; VPI-Blacksburg Water Plant; Virginia Automation Park; University Bookstore; Virginia Tech Carilion School of Medicine and Medical Research Institute building; Virginia Tech Research Center - Arlington building; Virginia Tech Museum of Natural History
          See RG 6/3/9 for War Memorial Chapel and Memorial Court (pylons, cenotaph).
        - RG 6/3/2b - Wallace Hall
        - RG 6/3/2b - War Memorial Hall
          May include War Memorial Gym
        - RG 6/3/2b - Whittemore Hall
      - RG 6/3/2c - Stone for VPI Buildings, Hokie Stone
      - RG 6/3/2d - Solitude
        See also RG 8/8/1b.
      - RG 6/3/2f - Grounds, General
        May include Campus landscape architect; Sycamore on Henderson Lawn; Campus trees and campus plants; International Peace Garden; Walkways; Tree Campus USA; Kiosks and navigation signage; William Addison Caldwell Historical Marker Unveiling; 125th Anniversary Grove; Pet Waste Station
      - RG 6/3/2f - Grounds, Stadium Woods
    - RG 6/3/3 - Airport
      May include Virginia Tech Aviation Hall of Fame
    - RG 6/3/4 - Parking
      May include General parking; Traffic; Office of Parking and Transportation; Fleet Services; Heads Up Hokies
      See also RG 6/3/8 for Roads.
      - RG 6/3/4 - Parking (Information)
      - RG 6/3/4 - Parking (Publications)
      - RG 6/3/4a - Traffic and Parking Regulations
    - RG 6/3/5 - Transportation
      May include Motor Pool / Carpool; Bicycles; Alternative Transportation; Roam NRV bike share; Blacksburg-Roanoke Smart-Way Shuttle
    - RG 6/3/6 - Sustainability
      The Office of Energy and Sustainability was split into separate offices of Energy Management and of Sustainability in 2018.
      May include Energy Crisis (1973-1974); Energy Conservation; Utilities / Electric Service; Campus Sustainability / Environmental Initiatives; Sustainability Week; Green RFP Program; LEED Certification [see also individual buildings in RG 6/3/2b]
      - RG 6/3/6a - Blacksburg-Virginia Tech (Blacksburg-VPI) Sanitation Authority
      - RG 6/3/6b - Coal Mines / Coal Power Plant and Protests
    - RG 6/3/7 - Virginia Tech Golf Course
      The Virginia Tech Golf Course opened on July 1, 1974, and the Virginia Tech Foundation acquired the Pete Dye River Course in 2002.
      May include Pete Dye River Course; Golf Shop/Pro Shop
    - RG 6/3/8 - Roads, Specific
      May include Animal Husbandry Road / Plantation Road
      See also RG 6/3/4.
    - RG 6/3/9 - War Memorial Chapel
      May include Memorial Court; Pylons; Cenotaph; Carillon [see also RG 6/3/2b, Burruss Hall]
    - RG 6/3/10 - Printing Department
      May include Campus Mail Service; Hokie Print
    - RG 6/3/11 - Virginia Tech Recycling (VTR) [items also in Oversize Box 1]
    - RG 6/3/12 - Drillfield
      May include the April 16th Memorial
      See also RG 6/3/2 for university grounds.
    - RG 6/3/13 - University Planning
      The Office of University Planning was established as the Office of Campus Planning, Space, and Real Estate in 2010, when the offices of Real Estate Management and the University Architect merged.
      May include University Architect
      See also RG 6/2; RG 6/3.
  - RG 6/4 - Department of Human Resources
    The Department of Human Resources was formerly the Personnel Department until June 1979 and the Department of Employee Relations after that. The Vice President for Human Resources position was created in August 2017.
    May include Commonwealth of Virginia Campaign (CVC); Office of Health and Safety Regulatory Programs; Staff (Non-professional); Hokies Live Well
    - RG 6/4 - Department of Human Resources (Information)
    - RG 6/4 - Department of Human Resources (Publications)
    - RG 6/4/1 - Director
    - RG 6/4/2 - Employment Division
      May include Dual Career Program
      - RG 6/4/2 - Employment Division (Information)
      - RG 6/4/2 - Employment Division (Publications)
    - RG 6/4/3 - Classification, Compensation, and Benefits Division
      May include Customer Service Recognition Program; Faculty-staff pay, wages, and salaries
      - RG 6/4/3 - Classification, Compensation, and Benefits Division (Information)
      - RG 6/4/3 - Classification, Compensation, and Benefits Division (Publications)
      - RG 6/4/3a - Citations and Awards
        May include Citations for Meritorious Service [see also RG 1]; President's Award for Excellence; Governor's Award; Service Recognition Program
      - RG 6/4/3b - Classified Employee Handbook
      - RG 6/4/3c - Tax Sheltered Annuities (includes U.S. Savings Bonds)
      - RG 6/4/3d - Retirement
      - RG 6/4/3e - Health Care Benefits
        May include Worker's Compensation; Insurance
        - RG 6/4/3e - Health Care Benefits (Information)
        - RG 6/4/3e - Health Care Benefits (Publications)
    - RG 6/4/4 - Employee Relations
      Employee Relations was formerly Employee Relations and Training Division.
    - RG 6/4/5 - Equity and Accessibility [obsolete, 2018; see RG 6/19] [items also in Oversize Box 1]
      The Affirmative Action/Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO) Division was renamed the Office of Equity and Inclusion. In July 2008, the Office of Multicultural Affairs [RG 8/11] merged into the Office for Equity and Inclusion. Later the office was renamed the Office for Equity and Accessibility. The office moved directly under the Senior Vice President for Operations and Administration in 2018 [RG 6/19].
      May include Compliance Review; Accessibility; Affirmative Action; Title IX and Sexual Harrassment Training; ADA and Accessibility Services; National Disability Employment Awareness Month
      See also RG 5/18/1; RG 6/19; RG 8/2/11; RG 8/11; RG 30/6; RG 30/7.
      - RG 6/4/5a - Women's Concerns (EEO) [obsolete, 2018; see RG 6/19]
        May include Coordinating Council for Women's Concerns
    - RG 6/4/6 - Payroll and Records Division [obsolete; see RG 7/2/2]
      The Payroll and Records Division moved to the Controller's Office [RG 7] in 1989.
      Although the Payroll and Records Division moved in 1989, some later items may be filed in RG 6/4/6.
      See also RG 6/4/6; RG 7; RG 7/2/2.
      - RG 6/4/6 - Payroll and Records Division (Information)
      - RG 6/4/6 - Payroll and Records Division (Publications)
    - RG 6/4/7 - University Organizational and Professional Development (UOPD)
      University Organizational and Professional Development (UOPD) was formerly Employee Career Development Program.
      May include Diversity Education and Initiatives; Diversity Development Institute; Staff Diversity Development Group; Employee Development Certificate Program; Management workshops
      - RG 6/4/7a - Credit Union of Virginia Tech [obsolete, 2003]
        The Credit Union of Virginia Tech, previously called the Virginia Tech Employees Credit Union, changed from an employer-based membership to community-based and became the Freedom First Credit Union in 2003.
    - RG 6/4/8 - Resource and Referral Service
      See also RG 6/4/11.
    - RG 6/4/9 - Consolidated Risk Management Services (CRMS) [obsolete, July 1992; see RG 7/7]
      The Consolidated Risk Management Services (CRMS) moved from the Office of Administration to the Controller's Office and became the Office of Risk Management in July 1992.
      May include Worker's Compensation
    - RG 6/4/10 - CommonHealth Employee Wellness Program
    - RG 6/4/11 - Office of Family Support
      The Office of Family Support has also been known as Family and Work/Life Resources.
  - RG 6/5 - Information Services [obsolete, July 1971; see RG 5/7 and RG 21/3]
    The Office of Information Services moved to Learning Resource Center [RG 5/7] in July 1971. It is also the predecessor of University Relations [RG 21/3].
    May include Motion Picture Unit at VPI; Techgram; Speaker Bureau
    See also RG 5/7; RG 21/3.
    - RG 6/5a - Press Releases (Agriculture)
    - RG 6/5b - Press Releases (General)
    - RG 6/5c - Information Services Name Change (University Name Controversy)
      May include University Name Committee
    - RG 6/5d - Mountains and Motorboards
      May include Context [obsolete]
    - RG 6/5e - Television/Radio
    - RG 6/5f - Virginia Tech-Blacksburg Relations
      May include Town Gown meetings; Baldwin Memorial Town and Gown Award
    - RG 6/5g - Photographic Services
  - RG 6/6 - Virginia Tech Services, Inc.
    Admininstrative History
    Formed in May 1967 as a non-profit organization, Virginia Tech Services, Inc., provides services and supplies to students, staff, and faculty. It was called VPI Facilities, Inc., until 1993. Sometimes, it has been referred to as University Services and Auxiliary Services or University Services and Auxiliary Enterprise. VT Services is in charge of the University Bookstores, which were previously administered by the Athletics Association.
    May include Follett Higher Education Group Inc.
    - RG 6/6/1 - University Bookstore [items also in Oversize Box 1]
    - RG 6/6/2 - Volume Two Bookstore
      May include Volume II Bookstore
    - RG 6/6/3 - Virginia Tech Merchandise
  - RG 6/7 - University Legal Counsel
    May include University Copyright Policy; Patent Policy
    See also RG 8/2/8a.
    - RG 6/7/3 - Lawsuits Involving Virginia Tech
      May include Title IX lawsuit over women's athletics
      - RG 6/7/3a - Brzonkala, Christy, lawsuit
      - RG 6/7/3b - Rogers, Craig A., lawsuit
      - RG 6/7/3c - Hokie Real Estate lawsuit
      - RG 6/7/3d - Sharon Maron, Erin Hofberg, and Getra Hanes lawsuit
  - RG 6/8 - Purchasing Department [obsolete, 2019; see RG 7/8]
    The Purchasing Department became the Procurement Department [RG 7/8].
    May include Loans to students
  - RG 6/9 - Central Stores
    May include Faculty Travel Expense Controversy
  - RG 6/10 - Classified Staff Affairs Committee
  - RG 6/11 - Virginia Government Employees' Association (VGA)
    - RG 6/11/1 - Virginia Tech Employees' Association (VTEA)
  - RG 6/12 - Staff Senate
    May include James D. McComas Staff Leadership Seminar; McComas Staff Leadership Award
  - RG 6/13 - Staff Appreciation Day (began Spring 1993)
  - RG 6/15 - Emergency Management
    May include VT Alerts; Emergency information and closures; Travel health notices; Weather emergencies; StormReady University; American Red Cross Month
  - RG 6/16 - Business Services
  - RG 6/17 - Vice President for Policy and Governance
    The position of Vice President for Policy and Governance was created in August 2017 under the Senior Vice President for Operations and Administration.
    May include President's Committee on Governance; VT Principles of Shared Governance
  - RG 6/18 - Vice President for Business Affairs
    The position of Vice President for Business Affairs was created in October 2018 under the Senior Vice President for Operations and Administration.
  - RG 6/19 - Office for Equity and Accessibility
    Previously in the Division of Human Resources [RG 6/4/5], the office moved to directly under the Senior Vice President for Operations and Administration in 2018.
    May include Title IX
    See also RG 5/18/1; RG 6/4/5; RG 8/2/11; RG 8/11.
- Record Group 7 - Office of Finance